

40 Allées de Tourny, 33000 Bordeaux, France

🛮 (+33)6 16 24 58 68 | 🗷 thomas.lentali@gmail.com | 🛅 thomas-lentali | 🗘 tlentali | 💃 tlentali | 🖹 tlentali

Summary

Data Scientist with 6+ years experience specializing in machine learning applied to a broad-spectrum of field like personalization/recommender system, search engine relevancy, bot detection, NLP, computer vision, financial fraud, gambling addiction detection, lifetime value prediction. My aim is to turn abstract knowledge into real world application and solving tools. I am an open minded nerd who act to stay sharp in his domain through helping my peers (top 1% on Stackoverflow in 2021), competitions (Kaggle competition expert) and open source contributions. And even if I am clearly driven by the data science field, I also defend the #1 Google ML Rule "Don't be afraid to launch a product without machine learning".

Work Experience _____

Betclic Group Bordeaux, France

DATA SCIENTIST

- Sport betting and casino personalization/recommender system
- Anti Money Laundering detection (ACAMS Certified Anti-money Laundering Specialist)
- Responsible gambling (addiction behavior) detection
- Lifetime value prediction

Using: Pandas, Scikit-learn, Pytorch, Tensorflow2/Keras, Shap, Airflow, AWS, Unittest/Pytest, Great Expectation...

Cdiscount Bordeaux, France

DATA SCIENTIST ADVISOR Nov. 2018 - Mai. 2019

- Massive customer clustering
- · Bot detection (pattern analysis)
- · Sentiment analysis (Natural Langage Processing)
- Object detection in picture (Mask-RCNN, MSCOCO dataset)

Cdiscount Bordeaux, France

DATA SCIENTIST Oct. 2016 - Oct. 2018

- · Search engine relevance
- · Recommendation engine
- Algorithms evaluation (A/B testing)
- · Focus on website's KPI improvment
- Python development (Scikit-learn, Numpy, Pandas, Scipy, Luigi etc)
- Hadoop Hive & SQL Databases

Cdiscount Bordeaux, France

DATA SCIENTIST INTERN Mar. 2016 - Sep. 2016

- · Marketing targeting: behavioral analysis and improvment of the search engine relevence through AB test, proof of concept personnalisation client (classification and clustering)
- Geographical data: Purchase forecasting by geographic zone
- · Statistical analysis: data enrichment with INSEE database, implementation and developement of geocoding tool
- · Intern innovation contest: Setting of a new operationnal service for the client, forcasting system of product storage to allow express delivery

Idaia Group Bordeaux, France

DATA SCIENTIST INTERN

Jun. 2015 - Aug. 2015

Sep. 2014 - Jul. 2016

Jun 2019 - current

· Sourcing, implementation and development of machine learning tools (mainly multiclass classification) in Python and Scala into Apache Spark large-scale data framework

Education

Toulon University

Bordeaux University Bordeaux, France

MSC. APPLIED MATHEMATICS • Optimization, operation research, machine learning, statistics, C++, Python, SQL

Toulon, France

Toulon University

BSC. APPLIED MATHEMATICS Sep. 2011 - Jul. 2012

• Statistics, probability, econometry, R, Matlab/Octave

Toulon, France BSC. PURE MATHEMATICS Sep. 2008 - Jul. 2011

· Algebra, analysis, topology, mesure theory, graph theory, C, Matlab/Octave, Wolfram Mathematica